Derick A. Gross

New York, NY | derick.gross@gmail.com | derickgross.github.io

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer in New York City, with several years experience architecting and building back-end solutions using cloud technologies. My most recent project, Apex, is an API proxy for microservices that provides one place to log and control service-to-service traffic.

EXPERIENCE

Co-Creator and Software Engineer, Apex 1/2020-4/2020 apex-api-proxy.github.io/

- · Designed solution architecture and created initial design drawings
- · Designed middleware to manage fault-handling logic, such as retries, backoff and timeout
- Designed relational database table schema for log storage
- Wrote middleware logic for request/response log storage
- Built admin user interface (React) and API (Node/Express)
- Created Docker images and YAML file for deployment with Docker and Docker Compose
- Integrated Node.js/Express.js solution with TimescaleDB, Redis, and React
- Wrote application docs, including instructions for deploying in AWS Elastic Container Service
- Co-authored comprehensive technical case study

Instructor Lead - Software Engineering, General Assembly 3/2019-6/2019

• Instructed students in full-stack software development: principles of OOP, MVC pattern, REST APIs, SQL, database design, Git, algorithms/data structures

Software Developer, True Earth Health Products 11/2016-3/2019

• Full stack, database and cloud development

Software Developer, Unytus 5/2016-10/2016

• Designed and built MVP for family-oriented service sharing

Director of Strategic Development, Habberstad Motorsport 7/2007-5/2015

• Executed special projects, events, and marketing initiatives for Executive Vice President

PROJECTS

- Dagpay (February 2019): Track payroll benefits deductions for employees. C# .NET Core web API featuring dependency injection, JWT authentication, Azure SQL database integration.
- WFM-QA: Event-sourced quality assurance (Fall 2018). Built controller routes, request objects and handlers (command pattern), and event applicators for Audit aggregate.

SKILLS and TECHNOLOGIES

AWS, Azure, Docker, JavaScript/Node.js, .NET Core, Ruby/Rails, PostgreSQL, TimescaleDB, Redis, SSMS, CosmosDB, Git/Github, REST APIs, jQuery, React/Redux, HTML5, CSS3

EDUCATION

- Launch School mastery-based software development (2016 2020)
- Columbia University Chemical Engineering (1999-2004, 20 credits remaining)